the benchpress arguably the most famous
exercise of all time and the only one
with its own holiday every Monday is
national benchpress day the benchpress
will help to develop upper body strength
and power using your chest and triceps
but like any exercise it only works if
you do it the right way and that way is
the buff dude way to perform grab the
bar with a slightly outside shoulder
grip making sure your forearms are in a
vertical line keep your hips firmly
placed on the bench with a slight arch
in the lower back about the width of
your hand in your feet flat on the
ground have your shoulders locked
downward and your shoulder blades
squeeze together as you lower the bar to
your sternum area make sure your elbows
and upper arms are at a 45 degree angle
to your torso drive the bar upward
keeping your torso and legs tight
congratulations you've just completed
the benchpress and are one step closer
to becoming a buff dude here is what not
to do while performing the benchpress
keep a small arch in the lower back
pressing your upper back and hips into
the bench do not arch your lower back
too much lifting your hips off the bench
keep your elbows and upper arms at a 45
degree angle to your torso do not keep
your elbows flared out wide forcing your
shoulders upward this will put strain on
the shoulder joint and could cause
injury grab the bar with a locked grip
with your thumbs firmly placed around
the bar do not grab the bar with a
suicide grip if the bar rolls off your
palms it could cause serious injury if
you use heavy weight use a spotter do
not live too much weight unassisted
alright now we know everything there is
to know about the infamous exercise time
to celebrate on national benchpress day
see you Monday dudes next week on buff
dudes
[Music]